

Carlos Torres

Trade // Data Analyst

Guadalajara, Jalisco

+52(33)12812194

□ cetalfa@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/carlos-t-649b361aa/

cetalfa.github.io/portfolio/

About Me

Specialist in Trade, Logistics & Supply Chain. Versatile individual with experience collecting, transforming, and organizing data for analysis. Excellent understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses, including SQL, Spreadsheets, Tableau, R and Python. Strong communication, organizational, and analytical skills. Recently completed the Google Data Analytics Certificate a rigorous, hands-on program that covers the entire scope of the data analysis process.

Professional Experience

Senior Imports Analyst

04 /2021 - Currently

Foxconn

- SQL Data mining, report development and data base modifications.
- Assist and support the Regional & Global Trade Compliance team with performing trade compliance audits, reporting, tariff clasification and other related regulatory trade compliance responsibilities.
- Customs Operations, Import & Export Pedimentos (IN,V1,AF,RT)

Import-Export Manager

(2009 to 2015) - (06/2020 - 04/2021)

JIT International Guadalajara

- Logistics operations & Imports-Exports liaison for 3PL, Customs Agents, Forwarders and Continental's supply chain analysts.
- Supply chain, daily control and download of EDI signal with materials requirements and forecast. Likewise, manual input in system for urgent materials orders.
- Manage of material flows systematically based on lean manufacturing, FIFO and just-in-time.
- Data processing of necessary records in SAP Prepare KPIs reports and presentations based on delivery schedules (ETAs), transit metrics, inventories and backlogs for Vendors and Continental.
- Knowledge of temporary, virtual, definitive Pedimentos and regime change: IN, V1, A1, RT, R1, F4
- Maintain the compliance record for IMMEX companies in software (Aranxel). Homologation of tariff classification and delivery of bimonthly reports of discharges.
- Procedures of changes of IMMEX, TIGIE, constant update in RGCM (General Rules of Foreign Trade).

Logistics Analyst

05/2019 - 09/2019

Ciena Corporation

- Collaboration with Global internal business units in order to generate all shipping documents for imports and exports around the world.
- Review performance transit metrics for inbound raw materials on a regular basis, identifying opportunities for improvement.
- Responsible to manage overall KPIs indicators such as supplier's delivery performance times.
- Track suppliers outgoing/incoming shipments, backlogs, mode of transportation and recovery plans when critical supply situations arise.

Customs Brokerage

2008 - 2009

Expeditors International

- Importation and Exportation of Goods. Prepare customs documentation and ensure that shipments meet all applicable laws to facilitate the import and export of goods.
- Determine customs duties and taxes payable and process payments on behalf of the clients.

Technological Proficiencies

- SOL
- Tableu
- R
- Python
- Excel, Power Point, Outlook, Word, Access
- HTML & CSS
- SAP (ERP)
- Oracle (ERP)
- Aranxel & ZOE (Inventory Control in Foreign Trade)

Education

Master's Degree in International Trade

2015 - 2017

Keimyung University

Bachelor's Degree in International Business

University of Guadalajara

Academic Honors & Seminars

- Google Data Analytics Certification 2022.
- Korean Government Scholarship Program award holder from September 2015 until February 2017.
- 2010 Seminar "Audits in Foreign Trade" course taught by Baker & McKenzie.
- "Incoterm Rules 2010" seminar by the International Chamber of Commerce ICC.
- Diploma awarded upon successful completion on the program "Developments of Qualifications in the Area of Scientific Investigation". Held from September to December 2009 with 150 hours, University of Guadalajara, Mexico.
- 2009 "Recommendations for Successfully Attending a Home Visit in Foreign Trade Matters". Held at the Expo Guadalajara Business Center Facilities by AIMMO

Languages

- Spanish: Native Speaker
- English: TOEFL IBT TEST score 101 points (Advance Level)
- Korean: TOPIK TEST level 3 (Intermediate Level)
- German: GOETHE-ZERTIFIKAT level A1 (Beginner Level)